# Jinhyuk Yoon

#### Geekble

5<sup>th</sup> Floor, C5, 77, Cheongam-ro, Nam-gu, Pohang, Gyeongbuk, South Korea

jinhyukyoon@postech.ac.kr https://www.jinhyukyoon.com

I'm a science communicator and engineer developing education contents through the use of my engineering background so people can physically participate and can learn scientific knowledge effectually. With deep interests in technology and education, I've been exploring the way of immersive learning experience through science communication and human-computer interaction. My contents for public speaking, elementary education, stage performance and video art have been successfully delivering knowledge about science and technology.

### **Professional Experience**

Geekble Mar 2019 – Present

Contents Development Manager

Developing experience-based activity contents about chemistry and artificial intelligence for middle school students using making activity, science experiment, and YouTube video contents.

#### **POSTECH, Haptics and Virtual Reality Laboratory**

Feb 2019 - Present

Undergraduate Research Assistant

Augmenting user's tactile perception on button pressing through vibrotactile actuation.

## Samsung Electronics, Digital Appliances, Core Component R&D Lab

Jan 2019 - Feb 2019

Mechanical Design Intern

Simplified design process of creating an appliance and helped engineers to explain physical phenomena to other division members through Interactive Torque Designer which interprets dynamics with an uncomplicated graphic.

**Sovoro** Jan 2018 – Apr 2018

**Communications Manager** 

Improved educational circumstance of hearing impaired as allowing them to understand the contents of usual class or seminar through conducting UI/UX research and designing the real-time transcript software.

### Korea Foundation for the Advancement of Science & Creativity

May 2016 - Jan 2018

Science Communicator

Succeeded effective understanding on the knowledge of mechanical engineering for elementary, middle school, high school students and adult through public speech and stage performance with participation of audience.

### Asan Medical Center, Biomedical Engineering Research Center

Aug 2017 - Sep 2017

Research Intern

Designed concept prototype of Ankle Rehabilitation Assistant which analyzes ankle torque and provides rehabilitative movement.

### **Leadership Experience**

### **POSTECH, Department of Mechanical Engineering**

Jan 2016 - Mar 2017

Student President

Directed departmental level of general meeting, student membership training, and professor appreciation banquet, and the first inter-university association program with KAIST.

### **POSTECH, Student Election Committee**

Sep 2016 - Nov 2016

Chairman

Organized the student election committee and run the election for central student president.

TEDxPOSTECH Nov 2014 – Nov 2015

Director

Organized talk conference that closed after 50 seconds of regular application through team building, speaker and sponsor contact, stage planning and facilitating on the event.

## **Education**

### **Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering**

2014 - Present

Pohang University of Science and Technology (POSTECH)

Candidate for Minor in Industrial Management Engineering. Expect to graduate with Magna Cum Laude.

## **Awards and Honors**

Commission Letter 2016

Minister of Ministry of Science & ICT commissioned me as a science communicator

Finalist 2016

Nationwide Top 11 of the 3rd FameLab Korea

Runners Up Artience Creation Challenge 30x30 hosted by British Council	2017
Honorable Mention 3 Minutes Science Speech Contest hosted by POSTECH	2015
Student of the Year POSTECH, Department of Mechanical Engineering	2015, 2016
The 4 <sup>th</sup> Prize The 2 <sup>nd</sup> POSTECH Hackathon	2016
National Academic Excellence Scholarship Korea Student Aid Foundation, Full-tuition	2016 – 2019
KT&G Foundation Scholarship POSTECH	2016
Jigok Scholarship POSTECH, Full-tuition	2014 – 2016

## **Selected Talks**

Keynote Speech, "About Experience", POSTECH Alumni Conference for Freshman, Pohang	2018
Keynote Speech, "Engineering and Science Communication", The 5th Integrated Science Leading Teacher Training, Yeongcheon	2016
Keynote Speech, "About Science Communication", National Youth Science Exploration Competition, Gyeongju	2016
Talk, "Regain the lost life", Suseong-gu Gosan Library, Daegu	2018
Talk, "Regain the lost life", KIST Science Station, Seoul	2017
Talk, "Space food", The 13th Bohyeonsan Starlight Festival, Yeongcheon	2016
Talk, "Science, Engineering and Me", Seongji High School, Yongin	2017
Talk, "Communicate with Science", Mulgeum High School, Yangsan	2017
Talk, "Talk with Odd Engineering Student", Samsung Girl's High School, Busan	2017

## **Publications**

### **To My Students, To My Teachers**

Andrea Sohn and Jinhyuk Yoon, The Korea Fulbright Infusion, Vol 6, 2013, 39 – 41.

### **About Mechanical Engineering**

Jinhyuk Yoon, POSTECHIAN, Spring, 2016, 30 – 31.

### **TEDxPOSTECH Brightened by Passion**

Jinhyuk Yoon, POSTECHIAN, Winter, 2015, 34 – 35.

## **Skills and Tools**

#### **Programming Language**

C, C++, JAVA, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MATLAB

#### **Graphic Design**

Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, Premiere, After Effects, InDesign

### 3D Design & Analysis

Solidworks, NX